<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>C&amp;C Remastered for Vortex – Usage</title><link>/docs/usage/</link><description>Recent content in Usage on C&amp;C Remastered for Vortex</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/docs/usage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Installation</title><link>/docs/usage/installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/usage/installation/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="quick-start">Quick Start&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The fastest way to get started is to just open the Games page in Vortex and scroll down through the unmanaged games. You should see an entry for C&amp;amp;C Remastered Collection in there. Click Manage on that entry and follow the prompts to install the extension and restart Vortex. You should be good to go and try &lt;a href="../../docs/usage/mods">installing some mods&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="installing-the-extension">Installing the Extension&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If the quick start doesn't work or you want to install the extension yourself, there's a couple of different ways to do that! Unless you've got a pretty specific use case, you'll probably want one of the two automatic methods, but manual installation is available as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="automatic-installation">Automatic Installation&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is the easiest way to install!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Open up Vortex, and open the Extensions panel from the left sidebar.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click &lt;strong>Find more&lt;/strong> to open the list of Extensions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find &lt;strong>Command and Conquer Remastered Support&lt;/strong> and click &lt;em>Install&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait for the extension to install and &lt;strong>restart Vortex&lt;/strong> when prompted.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Once Vortex has restarted, just click the Manage button on C&amp;amp;C Remastered in your Games screen and you're ready to &lt;a href="../../docs/usage/mods">install some mods&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="semi-automatic-installation">Semi-Automatic Installation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you can't install directly from the Extensions screen, you can instead install from the archive.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Download the archive from &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/site/mods/133?tab=files">Nexus Mods&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://https://github.com/agc93/vortex-cncremastered/releases">GitHub&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the Extensions panel in Vortex&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;em>Drop File(s)&lt;/em> box in the corner and locate the archive you downloaded.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wait for the extension to install and &lt;strong>restart Vortex&lt;/strong> when prompted.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Once Vortex has restarted, just click the Manage button on C&amp;amp;C Remastered in your Games screen and you're ready to &lt;a href="../../docs/usage/mods">install some mods&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="manual-installation">Manual Installation&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Only attempt this if you &lt;em>absolutely&lt;/em> have to. It becomes much harder to debug and much harder to upgrade.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>If you want to install the extension yourself, you will have to install the actual extension files manually. Make sure you close Vortex before proceeding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, download the archive from &lt;a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/site/mods/133?tab=files">Nexus Mods&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://https://github.com/agc93/vortex-cncremastered/actions">GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next, unpack the archive to somewhere convenient. You should have a directory named &lt;code>game-cncremastered&lt;/code> with four files inside:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>info.json&lt;/li>
&lt;li>index.js&lt;/li>
&lt;li>gameart.png&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Now, copy the whole directory to your Vortex folder. You can easily open your Vortex folder by opening a new File Explorer window and entering the following in to the location bar: &lt;code>%APPDATA%/Vortex&lt;/code> and then opening the &lt;code>plugins&lt;/code> directory (create it if it doesn’t exist).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you’re done, you should have four files at the following locations:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">C:\Users\&amp;lt;your-user-name-here&amp;gt;\AppData\Roaming\Vortex\plugins\game-cncremastered\info.json
C:\Users\&amp;lt;your-user-name-here&amp;gt;\AppData\Roaming\Vortex\plugins\game-cncremastered\index.js
C:\Users\&amp;lt;your-user-name-here&amp;gt;\AppData\Roaming\Vortex\plugins\game-cncremastered\gameart.png
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>With those files in place, you're clear to start Vortex and you should see the C&amp;amp;C Remastered icon in the Games screen light up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Installing Mods</title><link>/docs/usage/mods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/usage/mods/</guid><description>
&lt;p>At it's core, installing mods is roughly the same as any Vortex-enabled game, once you've added C&amp;amp;C Remastered as a managed game in Vortex.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you haven't already, open the Games screen and click the &lt;strong>Manage&lt;/strong> button on the C&amp;amp;C Remastered icon under &lt;em>Unmanaged&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Remember that mods still need to be enabled in-game from the Options ▶ Mods menu!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="installing-from-nexus-mods">Installing from Nexus Mods&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you're installing mods from Nexus Mods, you can use the &amp;ldquo;Vortex&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Download with Mod Manager&amp;rdquo; buttons on the mod page to automatically open Vortex and download the mod. Simply Install and Enable like usual and you should be good to go.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="install-from-archives">Install from archives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can also download mod archives directly from Nexus Mods or anywhere else you like and install them with Vortex. Simply use the &lt;em>Install From File&lt;/em> button in the toolbar or drop them onto the drop zone at the bottom of the Vortex window.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Be aware that installing from non-Nexus archives will often not include the full metadata. You can double-click the mod in the mod list to change its details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Please note that &amp;ldquo;raw&amp;rdquo; mods that aren't packaged in an archive (for example, loose &lt;code>ini&lt;/code> files) aren't supported, but Vortex should offer to create an archive for you if you try and install them.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>